hi everybody welcome back to the channel
this is a classic rum raisin video I'm I
hate using the whole Gen X thing but I'm
an old fart so back in the 80s in the UK
rum raisin was a huge flavor it's it's
really gone downhill as far as
popularity is concerned but let's look
at the a little bit the history of it
and then we're just going to get on and
make it so stick around if you want to
see how to make the 80s favorite rum
raisin ice cream
we went to longleat so Safari Park slash
kind of I don't know what would you
describe as
Adventure Park
yeah something like that something for
the whole family to go to in Wiltshire
in the UK it's a lovely place
they have the Festival of Lights at
Christmas so we went there to see that
I'll put some pictures up here and as
you can see this was roll dial in Roald
Dahl inspired this year so it was really
really enjoyable and whilst there we
went into the shop which sold loads of
chocolates and sweets and all stuff like
that
and I saw rum raisin fudge
I'll open this noise
like I said rum raisin actually it's a
sicilian recipe originally it was called
Malaga I think back then but they didn't
use rum to soak the raisins in they used
you know probably some kind of wine or
something like that fortified wine Maybe
and it came over to the rest of Europe
during the 1900s and then eventually hit
the US in the 80s so you know USA had it
really really late in its time in the
80s I was stuffing my face with rum
raisin ice cream
but back then I remember it being
kind of strange as a kid you're you're
eating something with rum in the title
obviously there wasn't rum in it back
then it was rum flavoring
so since the 80s it's disappeared off
the shelves really in England it become
a bit more of a classic flavor the last
five or ten years people are starting to
get a bit of resurgence for it and
now as an adult
I can have as much rum as I want
and raisins
it's good fudge
raisins are actually really good in ice
cream because if you're using alcohol
you can soak them in that so you get
these real pockets of it but
let's just dive in I'll show you how we
make it
[Music]
to start your classic rum raisin ice
cream you're going to take your raisins
and your favorite rum it could be any
rum you like just needs to be quite a
strong flavor
you're going to put your rum in a pan
and then slowly start to warm that up
where you're going to add in your
raisins you're going to let them simmer
for at least five to ten minutes because
what you're trying to do is open the
pores of the raisins and allow that rum
to permeate inside you can let them sit
there for half an hour if you want
and then take them out of the pan put
them in a container and leave them
overnight that's quite important
[Music]
I've whilst your raisins and rum are
just sitting there nicely soaking up all
those flavors you can start to prepare
your ice cream base
here we're going to take our milk as
normal and here you can see me mixing up
my stabilizer with my dextrose we're
going to add that in along with our
sugar and slowly start to bring that up
to temperature
now for this recipe I've added the cream
in whilst it's on the hob and that is
purely because this cream was right at
the end of its life so just to be safe
I've heated the whole lot up together
once it's up to temperature around 60 to
70 degrees you're going to add in your
skim milk powder and make sure that's
fully incorporated into your liquids
once it's all completely homogenized
you're going to take it off the hob and
then put your ice cream base in a
container there you're just going to let
it cool down slightly and then put it in
the fridge to completely chill down
now the following day you're going to
take out your soaked raisins and you're
going to strain off any remaining rum
that's left in the container what you're
actually going to do is take your ice
cream base out the fridge and put that
remaining rum in it you don't want to do
it when it's hot and that's quite
important because you want to maintain
the alcohol in this rum you want as much
flavor and alcohol goodness as you can
stir that in nicely then what you're
going to do is put that in your ice
cream and sheet ice cream machine to
churn right at the end of your chain
you're gonna add in your raisins you can
add as many or as few as you like I've
gone to town and added quite a few as
you can see at that stage take it out
your machine load up your ice cream tubs
and then put them in a freezer to
completely harden off
and here we go it's just come out the
freezer the alcohol
means that it doesn't freeze solid and a
lot of people put vodka in their ice
creams to do this you don't need to do
that please don't do that but because
this recipe actually has alcohol in it
you need to be careful with how much
sugar you put in so we're just going to
get some scooped up and see how this
turned out
[Music]
scooped really well
looks really good loads of raisins in
there let's see what it tastes like
[Music]
thank you
that's so much better than I remember it
being
it's kind of a flavor that actually
someone else that makes ice cream
Free Living released this is a Christmas
flavor raisins obviously with rum is
quite synonymous with this you know
festive part of the year
these are Cape raisins
from South Africa I think not Cape Fear
reasons
[Music]
but they're really nice and juicy I mean
this one's massive
so they had a nice texture change in the
ice cream when you bite into that soft
raisin
they're really soft because they're full
of sugar but obviously you've then
permeated them with alcohol so they stay
completely soft in your ice cream so you
get this burst of rum your favorite rum
come out of it and because you've left
the base completely unflavored apart
from that small amount of rum it's not
an overpowering ice cream either
I think if you flavored that base with
something else
you could maybe add a bit of vanilla to
it just to bring some flavors forward
but I quite like that plainer ice cream
with the pockets of rum every time you
bite into one of those raisins
it's really nice you could you could
make rum raisin fudge and add that into
it if you really wanted to
much related because it's there
but
a classic flavor
rum raisin doesn't deserve to be put
aside
like it has done or has been for the
last 30 odd years Haagen-Dazs released
rum raisin in the US in the 80s it's now
becoming a little bit more popular than
it used to be
but it's always overtaken by other more
modern
hipster flavors so
talk about hipster flavors I've just
made something probably hipster flavored
but we'll deal with that another day
so if you like run raisin ice cream or
you're really fancy of making this
classic flavor let me know in the
comments below if this has worked out
for you thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like And subscribe you
can support us on Kofi I'll put the link
below as normal
hope you have a good festive season and
I'll see you all next time
foreign